<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="text.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>

<raw_text docid="WPE15_G00.11973" xmlns="http://ids-mannheim.de/ns/KorAP">
  <metadata file="metadata.xml" />
  <text>         Generation X, commonly abbreviated to Gen X, is the generation born after the Western Post–World War II baby boom. Demographers, historians, and commentators use birth dates ranging from the early 1960s to the early 1980s.  Origin of Term  File:RobertCapabyGerdaTaro.jpg Hungarian photographer Robert Capa referred to young adults of the mid 1950s as "Generation X"     File:Douglas Coupland Photo of Author.jpg Douglas Coupland popularized the term "Generation X" in a novel about the lifestyles of young adults in the late 1980s.    The term Generation X was coined by the Magnum photographer Robert Capa in the early 1950s. He used it later as a title for a photo-essay about young men and women growing up immediately after the Second World War. The project first appeared in  Picture Post  (UK) and Holiday (US) in 1953. Describing his intention, Capa said "We named this unknown generation, The Generation X, and even in our first enthusiasm we realised that we had something far bigger than our talents and pockets could cope with." &lt;ref&gt;[http://books.google.com/books?id=v10ZUR_Ca3EC&amp;amp;pg=PA32&amp;amp;dq=generation+x+holiday&amp;amp;cd=1#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=generation%20x%20holiday&amp;amp;f=false GenXegesis: essays on alternative youth (sub)culture By John McAllister Ulrich, Andrea L. Harris] p. 5.&lt;/ref&gt;   The name was popularized by Canadian author Douglas Coupland's 1991 novel,  Generation X: Tales for an Accelerated Culture , concerning young adults during the late 1980s and their lifestyles.&lt;ref name="Ulrich"&gt;{{cite book |url=http://books.google.com/books?id=v10ZUR_Ca3EC&amp;amp;lpg=PA3&amp;amp;pg=PA3#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false |title=GenXegesis: essays on alternative youth |chapter=Introduction: A (Sub)cultural Genealogy |author=Ulrich, John |editor=Andrea L. Harris |page=3|isbn=9780879728625 |year=2003 }}&lt;/ref&gt; While Coupland's book helped to popularize the phrase Generation X in a 1989 magazine article &lt;ref&gt;Coupland, Doug. "[http://joeclark.org/dossiers/GenerationX.pdf Generation X]." ''Vista'', 1989.&lt;/ref&gt; he erroneously attributed it to English rock musician Billy Idol.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|last=Idol|first=Billy|title=Eyes Without a Face|url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9OFpfTd0EIs|accessdate=23 March 2013}}&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|last=Idol|first=Billy|title=Rebel Yell|url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VdphvuyaV_I|accessdate=23 March 2013}}&lt;/ref&gt; In fact, Idol&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|title=Catch My Fall|url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EiMFvx43vpw|accessdate=18 December 2014}}&lt;/ref&gt; had been a member of the punk band Generation X from 1976 to 1981, which was named after Deverson and Hamblett's 1965 sociology book on British youth,  Generation X &lt;ref&gt;Hamblett, Charles, and Jane Deverson. "generation X". Greenwich, Conn.: Fawcett Publications, 1964.&lt;/ref&gt;—a copy of which was owned by Idol's mother.&lt;ref&gt;[http://punk77.co.uk/groups/generationx.htm Generation X – A Punk History with Pictures]&lt;/ref&gt;  Characteristics and demographics  Gen X is the generation born after the Western post–World War II baby boom describing a generational change from the Baby Boomers.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|last=Miller|first=Jon D.|title=The Generation X Report: Active, Balanced, and Happy: These young Americans are not bowling alone|url=http://lsay.org/GenX_Rept_Iss1.pdf|publisher=University of Michigan, Longitudinal Study of American Youth, funded by the National Science Foundation|accessdate=October 23, 2012}}&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|last=Jon D.|first=Miller|title=Xplaining Gen X – National Science Foundation Sponsored Webcast|url=http://www.nsf.gov/news/news_summ.jsp?cntn_id=122044|publisher=National Science Foundation|accessdate=2011-10-19}}&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref name="Encyclopedia of Identity"&gt;[http://books.google.com/books?id=C2WmSCOBR2IC&amp;amp;pg=PA307&amp;amp;dq=%22Generation+X%22+%22baby+bust%22&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ei=1COvTNWNIsSclgfgjMHnDw&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;oi=book_result&amp;amp;ct=result&amp;amp;resnum=2&amp;amp;ved=0CDEQ6AEwAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=%22Generation%20X%22%20%22baby%20bust%22&amp;amp;f=false Encyclopedia of Identity] By Ronald L. Jackson, II&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref name="r5"&gt;Strauss, William &amp;amp; Howe, Neil. ''Generations: The History of America's Future, 1584 to 2069''. Perennial, 1992 (Reprint). ISBN 0-688-11912-3 p. 318 &amp;amp; p. 324&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news |url=http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2007/11/20/opinion/main3528584.shtml?tag=contentMain;contentBody/wp-dyn/content/article/2008/02/29/AR2008022903658_pf.html |title=Obama's Generation X Factor |last=Chaudhry |first=Alexandra |date=2012-04-30 |publisher=[[Time (magazine)|Time]] |accessdate=2012-05-01 }}&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news| url=http://www.boston.com/bostonglobe/ideas/brainiac/2008/01/generation_x.html | work=Boston Globe | title=The Original Generation X, 1954–63 | date=2008-01-10| accessdate=24 July 2012 | first=Joshua | last=Glenn}}&lt;/ref&gt;  In a 2012 article for the Joint Center for Housing Studies of Harvard University, George Masnick wrote that the "Census counted 82.1 million" Gen Xers in the U.S. The Harvard Center uses 1965 to 1984 to define Gen X so that Boomers, Xers and Millennials "cover equal 20-year age spans".&lt;ref name="Masnick"&gt;{{cite web|last=Masnick|first=George|title=Defining the Generations|url=http://housingperspectives.blogspot.com/2012/11/defining-generations.html|publisher=Harvard Joint Center for Housing Studies|accessdate=29 May 2013}}&lt;/ref&gt; Masnick concluded that immigration filled in any birth year deficits during low fertility years of the late 1960s and early 1970s &lt;ref name="Masnick"&gt;&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref name="U.S. Census"&gt;{{cite web|title=U.S. Census Age and Sex Composition: 2010|url=http://www.census.gov/prod/cen2010/briefs/c2010br-03.pdf|publisher=U.S. Census|accessdate=13 September 2013|page=4|date=2011-05-11}}&lt;/ref&gt;  Jon Miller at the Longitudinal Study of American Youth at the University of Michigan wrote that "Generation X refers to adults born between 1961 and 1981" and it "includes 84 million people" in the U.S.&lt;ref name="U.S. Census"&gt;&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|last=Miller|first=Jon|title=The Generation X Report: Active, Balanced, and Happy: These Young Americans are not Bowling Alone|url=http://lsay.org/GenX_Rept_Iss1.pdf|publisher=Longitudinal Study of American Youth – University Of Michigan|accessdate=29 May 2013|page=1|date=Fall 2011}}&lt;/ref&gt;  In 2011 "The Generation X Report" (based on annual surveys used in the Longitudinal Study of today's adults) found Gen Xers, defined in the report as people born between 1961 and 1981, to be highly educated, active, balanced, happy and family oriented. The study contrasted with the slacker, disenfranchised stereotype associated with youth in the 1970s and 1980s.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news| url=http://articles.cnn.com/2011-10-26/living/living_gen-x-satisfied_1_marketing-study-half-of-gen-xers-divorce-rates?_s=PM:LIVING | work=CNN | title=Study says Generation X is balanced and happy | date=2011-10-26 | accessdate=2012-06-25 | first1=Alene | last1=Dawson}}&lt;/ref&gt; Various questions and responses from approximately 4,000 people who were surveyed each year from 1987 through 2010 made up the study.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.lsay.org/ |title=LSAY |publisher=LSAY |accessdate=2014-05-19}}&lt;/ref&gt; Clive Thompson, writing in  Wired  in 2014 claimed that the differences between Generation X and its predecessors had been over-hyped, quoting Kali Trzesniewski, a scholar of life-span changes, as saying that the basic personality metrics of Americans had remained stable for decades.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news|last=Thompson|first=Clive|title=Congrats, Millennials. Now It's Your Turn to Be Vilified|url=http://www.wired.com/opinion/2014/01/thompson_generation/|accessdate=2 March 2014|newspaper=Wired|date=31 January 2014}}&lt;/ref&gt;  In 2012, the Corporation for National and Community Service ranked Gen X volunteer rates in the U.S. at "29.4% per year", the highest compared with other generations. The rankings were based on a three-year moving average between 2009 and 2011.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|title=Volunteering and Civic Life in America: Generation X Volunteer Rates|url=http://www.volunteeringinamerica.gov/rankings/States/Generation-X-Volunteer-Rates/2011|publisher=Corporation for National and Community Service|accessdate=31 January 2013|date=November 27, 2012}}&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|title=Volunteering in the United States|url=http://www.bls.gov/news.release/pdf/volun.pdf|publisher=Bureau of Labor Statistics – U.S. Department of Labor|accessdate=20 April 2013|page=1|date=Feb 22, 2013}}&lt;/ref&gt;  In the preface to Generation X Goes Global: Mapping a Youth Culture in Motion, a collection of global essays, Professor Christine Henseler summarizes it as "a generation whose worldview is based on change, on the need to combat corruption, dictatorships, abuse, AIDS, a generation in search of human dignity and individual freedom, the need for stability, love, tolerance, and human rights for all".&lt;ref&gt;[http://www.generationxgoesglobal.com/index.html Generation X Goes Global: Mapping a Youth Culture in Motion], Christine Henseler, Ed.; Routledge, August 2012&lt;/ref&gt;  In cinema, directors Quentin Tarantino, David Fincher, Jane Campion, Steven Soderbergh,&lt;ref&gt;{{cite book|last=Hanson|first=Peter|title=The Cinema of Generation X: A Critical Study of Films and Directors|year=2002|publisher=McFarland and Company|location=North Carolina and London|isbn=0-7864-1334-4}}&lt;/ref&gt; Kevin Smith,&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news |url=http://www.viewaskew.com/press/time/article.html|title=MY GENERATION BELIEVES WE CAN DO ANYTHING |last=TIME |first=Magazine |date=1998-06-09|publisher=View Askew |accessdate=2011-09-18 }}&lt;/ref&gt; Richard Linklater&lt;ref&gt;Richard Linklater, ''Slacker'', St Martins Griffin, 1992.&lt;/ref&gt; and Todd Solondz&lt;ref&gt;{{cite book | last = Tasker | first = Yvonne | title = Fifty Contemporary Film Directors (page 365) | publisher = [[Routledge]] | date = October 21, 2010 | isbn = 0415554330 }}&lt;/ref&gt; have been called Generation X filmmakers. Smith is most known for his View Askewniverse films, the flagship film being  Clerks , which is set in New Jersey circa 1994, and focuses on two bored, convenience-store clerks in their twenties. Linklater's  Slacker  similarly explores young adult characters who were more interested in philosophizing than settling with a long-term career and family. Solondz'  Welcome to the Dollhouse  touched on themes of school bullying, school violence, teen drug use, peer pressure and broken or dysfunctional families, set in a junior high school environment in New Jersey during the early to mid-1990s.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite book | last = Russell | first = Dominique | title = Rape In Art Cinema (page 130: "In this vein, Solondz' films, while set in the present, contain an array of objects and architectural styles that evoke Generation X's childhood and adolescence. Dawn (Heather Matarazzo) wears her hair tied up in a 1970s ponytail holder with large balls, despite the fact her brother works at a 1990 Macintosh computer, in a film that came out in 1996.") | publisher = [[Continuum International Publishing Group]] | date = March 25, 2010 | isbn = 082642967X }}&lt;/ref&gt; While not a member of Gen X himself, director John Hughes has been recognized as having created a series of classics "that an entire generation took ownership of with films like  The Breakfast Club ,&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|title=The Breakfast Club|url=http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0088847/}}&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|first1=Simple Minds|title=Don't You (Forget About Me)|url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CdqoNKCCt7A}}&lt;/ref&gt;  Sixteen Candles  and  Weird Science ".&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|last=Aronchick.|first=David|title=Happy Birthday John Hughes: The Voice of My So-Called 'Lost Generation' |url=http://www.huffingtonpost.com/david-aronchick/happy-birthday-john-hughes_b_2689002.html|work=Huff Post Entertainment|accessdate=5 March 2014}}&lt;/ref&gt;  Gen Xers are often called the MTV Generation.&lt;ref name="Isaksen 2002"&gt;{{cite news| url=http://findarticles.com/p/articles/mi_g1epc/is_tov/ai_2419100500/ | work=St. James Encyclopedia of Pop Culture | title=Generation X | first=Judy L. | last=Isaksen | year=2002}}&lt;/ref&gt; They experienced the emergence of music videos, new wave music, electronic music, synthpop, glam rock, heavy metal and the spin-off glam metal, punk rock and the spin-off pop punk, alternative rock, grunge,&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news| url=http://savannahnow.com/stories/040804/LOC_grunge.shtml | work=Savannah Now | title=Out: 10 years after Cobain, can grunge speak to spirit of a generation? | date=April 2004 | accessdate=2012-12-12}}&lt;/ref&gt; and hip hop.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news| url=http://www.nytimes.com/2011/08/07/magazine/the-gen-x-nostalgia-boom.html?pagewanted | work=New York Times | title=My So Called Adulthood | date=2011-08-04 | accessdate=2011-08-25 | first1=Carl | last1=Wilson}}&lt;/ref&gt;  Compared with previous generations, Generation X represents a more heterogeneous generation, embracing social diversity in terms of such characteristics as race, class, religion, ethnicity, culture, language, gender identity, and sexual orientation.&lt;ref name="Isaksen 2002"&gt;&lt;/ref&gt;  Unlike their parents who challenged leaders with an intent to replace them, Gen Xers are less likely to idolize leaders and are more inclined to work toward long-term institutional and systematic change through economic, media and consumer actions.&lt;ref&gt;[http://www.notterconsulting.com/Articles/generationaldive.html ]{{dead link|date=May 2014}}&lt;/ref&gt;  The U.S. Census Bureau reports that Generation X holds the highest education levels when looking at current age groups.&lt;ref&gt;.U.S. Census Bureau, in their 2009 Statistical Abstract.&lt;/ref&gt;  Pursuant to a study by Elwood Carlson on "how different generations respond in unique ways to common problems in some political, social, and consumption choices", the Population Reference Bureau, a private demographic research organization based in Washington, D.C., cited Generation X birth years as falling between 1965 and 1982.&lt;ref name="20th - Century U.S. Generations"&gt;{{cite web|title=20th – Century U.S. Generations|url=http://www.prb.org/pdf09/64.1generations.pdf}}&lt;/ref&gt; On the first page of the study, authors William Strauss and Neil Howe's definition of a "cohort generation" is cited.&lt;ref name="20th - Century U.S. Generations"&gt;&lt;/ref&gt; They define Generation X by the years 1961 to 1981.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite book|last=Strauss|first=William|title=Generations: The History of Americas Future, 1584 to 2069|year=1991|publisher=Harper Perennial|location=New York |isbn=0-688-11912-3|page=317|author2=Neil Howe}}&lt;/ref&gt;  In 2008,  Details  magazine editor-at-large Jeff Gordinier released his book X Saves the World -- How Generation X Got the Shaft but Can Still Keep Everything from Sucking.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite book|last=Gordinier|first=Jeff|title=X Saves the World -- How Generation X Got the Shaft but Can Still Keep Everything From Sucking|year=2008|publisher=Penguin Group|location=New York, NY|isbn=978-0-670-01858-1|pages=Cover}}&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|last=Gordinier|first=Jeff|title=Author Jeff Gordinier Discusses X Saves the World|url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MPdEgwOsvDk|publisher=YouTube|accessdate=November 2, 2012}}&lt;/ref&gt;  Economy Studies done by Pew Charitable Trusts, the American Enterprise Institute, the Brookings Institution, the Heritage Foundation and the Urban Institute challenged the notion that each generation will be better off than the one that preceded it.&lt;ref name="Isabel Sawhill, Ph.D 2007"&gt;{{cite web|title=Economic Mobility: Is the American Dream Alive and Well?|url=http://www.brookings.edu/views/papers/sawhill/200705.pdf|accessdate=22 March 2013|author=Isabel Sawhill, Ph.D|author2=John E. Morton|year=2007}}&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|last=Steuerle|first=Eugene|title=Lost Generations? Wealth Building Among Young Americans|url=http://www.urban.org/UploadedPDF/412766-Lost-Generations-Wealth-Building-Among-Young-Americans.pdf|publisher=Urban Institute|accessdate=22 March 2013 |author2=Signe-Mary McKernan |author3=Caroline Ratcliffe |author4=Sisi Zhang|year=2013}}&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt;[http://www.economicmobility.org/ Economic Mobility Project]&lt;/ref&gt;  A report titled Economic Mobility: Is the American Dream Alive and Well? focused on the income of males 30–39 in 2004 (those born April 1964March 1974). The study was released on May 25, 2007 and emphasized that this generation's men made less (by 12%) than their fathers had at that same age in 1974, thus reversing a historical trend. It concluded that per year increases in household income generated by fathers/sons have slowed (from an average of 0.9% to 0.3%), barely keeping pace with inflation. "Family incomes have risen though (over the period 1947 to 2005) because more women have gone to work, supporting the incomes of men, by adding a second earner to the family. And as with male income, the trend is downward".&lt;ref name="Isabel Sawhill, Ph.D 2007"&gt;&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news| url=http://money.cnn.com/2007/05/25/pf/mobility_study/index.htm?cnn=yes | work=CNN | title=Making less than dad did | date=2007-05-25 | accessdate=2010-05-03 | first1=David | last1=Ellis}}&lt;/ref&gt;   Generation Flux is a neologism and psychographic designation coined by  Fast Company  for American employees who need to make several changes in career throughout their working lives because of the chaotic nature of the job market following the Financial crisis of 2007–08. Those in "Generation Flux" have birth years in the ranges of Gen X and Millennials.  Entrepreneurship According to authors Michael Hais and Morley Winograd, "small businesses and the entrepreneurial spirit that Gen Xers embody have become one of the most popular institutions in America. There's been a recent shift in consumer behavior and Gen Xers will join the “idealist generation” in encouraging the celebration of individual effort and business risk-taking. As a result, Xers will spark a renaissance of entrepreneurship in economic life, even as overall confidence in economic institutions declines. Customers, and their needs and wants (including Millennials) will become the North Star for an entire new generation of entrepreneurs".&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|title=Why Generation X is Sparking a Renaissance in Entrepreneurship|url=http://www.beinkandescent.com/articles/942/GenX|accessdate=22 April 2013|author=Morley Winograd|author2=Michael Hais|year=2012}}&lt;/ref&gt;  United Kingdom A 2008 article by  The Observer , cites the Generation X birth years as falling between 1965 and 1982; the same article later describes Millennials as being born between 1982 and 2002. The writer states that Generation Xers were "labelled by some" as the me generation of the Eighties."&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news| url=http://www.guardian.co.uk/money/2008/may/25/workandcareers.worklifebalance | work=The Guardian | title=They don't live for work ... they work to live | date=2008-05-25 | accessdate=2011-07-21 | first1=Anushka | last1=Ashthana | location=London}}&lt;/ref&gt; Another piece written by a  Guardian  journalist in 2011 uses 1961 to 1981 for this generation.     The Telegraph  cites Gen X birth dates as falling between a longer time span (1965–1985),&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news| url=http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/uknews/1573570/Generation-X-having-less-sex.html | work=The Telegraph | title=Generation X 'having less sex' | date=2007-12-24 | accessdate=2011-07-21 | first1=Kate | last1=Devlin | location=London}}&lt;/ref&gt; In 2007,  The Independent  estimated an earlier range of birth dates (1963–1978) compared to other writers or researchers.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news| url=http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/this-britain/generation-x-the-slackers-who-changed-the-world-436651.html | work=The Independent | title=Generation X: The slackers who changed the world | date=2007-02-18 | accessdate=2011-07-21 | first1= | last1=A | location=London}}&lt;/ref&gt; However, the newspaper's 2010 article titled "Generation X: A mid-life crisis" uses the 1961 to 1981 date range.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news | first = Susie | last = Mesure | title = Generation X: A mid-life crisis | date = 2010-05-23 | publisher = Independent Print Limited | url = http://www.independent.co.uk/news/people/news/generation-x-a-midlife-crisis-1980482.html | work = The Independent | accessdate = 2014-02-15 | quote = The Independent on Sunday tested his thesis with a straw poll of Gen Xers (anyone born between 1961 and 1981) to see whether the slacker mid-life crisis has hit the UK.}}&lt;/ref&gt; The  BBC News  article about a lack of "mid-career volunteers" in their 20s provides a Generation X age range, which, being written in 2007, would suggest birth years that fall between 1962 and 1982.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news| url=http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/uk_news/6275599.stm | work=BBC News | title=Teaching 'Generation X' a lesson | date=2007-01-19 | accessdate=2011-07-23 | first1= | last1=A}}&lt;/ref&gt;  A  Daily Express  article in December 2013 discusses the impact the recession has had on the generation "born between 1961 and 1981." Despite a good degree and desired job skills, "they discovered that there is no job security and everywhere there are cutbacks on staff, salaries and benefits," Jan Etherington writes.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news | first = Jan | last = Etherington | title = Fortysomethings are bearing the brunt of the recession | date = 2013-12-18 | publisher = [[Northern and Shell Media]] | url = http://www.express.co.uk/comment/expresscomment/449308/Fortysomethings-are-bearing-the-brunt-of-the-recession | work = [[Daily Express]] | accessdate = 2014-02-15 | quote = Known as Generation X (born between 1961 and 1981), my children and their friends grew up politically aware, energetic, full of hope and ambition.}}&lt;/ref&gt;  In 2014, The  International Business Times  UK edition reported that top British graduates today were "more likely to be attracted to working independently as a freelancer for multiple companies, than looking for a job for life with one employer."&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news | first = Ian | last = Silvera | title = Top Performing British Graduates Turned Off by Traditional Jobs | date = 2014-02-05 | publisher = [[IBT Media]] | url = http://www.ibtimes.co.uk/top-performing-british-graduates-turned-off-by-traditional-jobs-1435195 | work = International Business Times UK | accessdate = 2014-02-15 | quote = generation X (born between 1961 and 1981)... generation Y graduates (born between 1982 and 1993)}}&lt;/ref&gt;  Canada  David Foot, author and University of Toronto professor, divides the generation born after the Baby Boomers into two groups in his book Boom Bust &amp;amp; Echo: How to Profit from the Coming Demographic Shift:&lt;ref&gt;{{cite book | author=Foot, David | title=Boom, Bust &amp;amp; Echo | url=http://www.footwork.com/book.html | publisher=Macfarlane Walter &amp;amp; Ross | year=1996 | isbn=0-921912-97-8 | pages=18–22}}&lt;/ref&gt; Generation X, born between 1960 and 1966; and the "Bust Generation", born between 1967 and 1979.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite journal | title = Generation X and Political Correctness: Ideological and Religious Transformation Among Students | journal = Canadian Journal of Sociology | date = Fall 1997 | first = Thomas Norman | last = Trenton | volume = 22 | issue = 4 | pages = 417–36 | url = http://www.cjsonline.ca/articles/trenton.htmL | accessdate = 2011-06-03 | quote = In Boom, Bust &amp;amp; Echo, Foot (1996: 18–22) divides youth into two groups: 'Generation X' born between 1960 and 1966 and the 'Bust Generation' born between 1967 and 1979.}}&lt;/ref&gt; Foot contends that those born between the periods of 1947–1966 were the Baby Boomers, where in Canada they were the largest boom of the industrialized world (relative to population).&lt;ref&gt;Foot, David. ''Boom, Bust &amp;amp; Echo.''Macfarlane Walter &amp;amp; Ross, 1996. ISBN 0-921912-97-8. p.19&lt;/ref&gt; This large boom complicated the job market for the upcoming generation.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|url=http://archives.cbc.ca/society/youth/topics/1209-6689/ |title=CBC Digital Archives |publisher=Archives.cbc.ca |accessdate=2014-05-19}}&lt;/ref&gt; However, it is also common in Canada to represent Generation Xers using the date ranges 1961–1981 or 1965–1981.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite journal | title = Destination Canada: Are We Doing Enough? | journal = Deloitte Tourism, Hospitality &amp;amp; Leisure Industry and Tourism Industry Association of Canada (TIAC) | year = 2009 | author = Deloitte &amp;amp; Touche LLP, Tourism Industry Association of Canada | pages = 1–16| id = | url = http://www.linkbc.ca/torc/downs1/Destionationcanadav3.pdf | accessdate = 2011-03-28 | quote = 67% are members of Generations X (1961–81) and Y (1982–2001), or the 'contemporary generations'}}&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web | url = http://www.bc.anglican.ca/pages/news/garynicolosimarch08.html | title = From Maintenance to Mission | accessdate = 2011-03-31 | last = Nicolosi | first = Gary | date = 2008-03 | work = The Anglican Diocese of British Columbia | quote = Generation X (born 1965–1981)}}&lt;/ref&gt;  Australia and New Zealand A  Sydney Morning Herald  article defined Gen X as "those born roughly between 1963–1980."&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news| url=http://www.smh.com.au/lifestyle/diet-and-fitness/talkin-bout-my-label-20110720-1ho7s.html | work=Sydney Morning Herald | title=Talkin' 'bout my label | date=2011-07-20 | accessdate=2011-12-18 | first1=Jane | last1=Holroyd}}&lt;/ref&gt; The Australian Bureau of Statistics use a 1965–1981 birth range to define Generation X.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite journal | title = Superannuation and the Under 40’s: Summary Report: Research Report on the Attitudes and Views of Generations X and Y on Superannuation. | journal = McCrindle Research | date = 2005-07-18 | first = Mark | last = McCrindle | quote = Generation X 1965–1981...Generation X comprises those aged between 24 and 40...Millennials 1982–2000...}}&lt;/ref&gt; According to generational demographers Bill Strauss and Neil Howe, "shorter birth year definitions are shorthand for fertility rates. Gen Xers (as a cultural generation) look beyond demographics to define themselves by a shared location in history, common beliefs, attitudes and values (and a common perceived membership). Defining Gen X purely by demographic bulges and busts (like the Census) misses key cultural indicators that a very different set of young people has come along. Commentators who set Millennial birth boundaries starting in the late-70s often make the same assumptions using fertility rates to define birth dates rather than shared beliefs, attitudes and values. Children born in the early 1960s and after had a very different coming of age experience than those born in the late 1950s. Some of the most influential cultural definers of Gen X were born during the period between 1961 and 1964."&lt;ref name="Generations"&gt;{{cite book|last=Howe|first=Neil|title=Generations|year=1991|publisher=Harper Perennial|location=New York|isbn=0-688-11912-3|pages=58–68}}&lt;/ref&gt;  Sources in New Zealand, including the country's labour statistics, define Gen X between the years 1965 and 1981.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news | first = David | last = Eames | title = Jumping the Generation Gap | date = 2008-03-06 | publisher = APN New Zealand Ltd | url = http://www.nzherald.co.nz/david-eames/news/article.cfm?a_id=211&amp;amp;objectid=10496379 | work = [[The New Zealand Herald]] | accessdate = 2011-03-31 | quote = Generation X (1965–1981) Cynical, pessimistic, individualist, no employer loyalty, self-sufficient, sceptical.}}&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt;{{cite journal | title = Tuning in to the Next Generation of Leaders | journal = InFinance | date = March 2011 | first = Dr. Colin | last = Pitt | volume = 125 | issue = 1 | page = 1| quote = Generation X: 1965–1981}}&lt;/ref&gt; According to a December 2013 article from  The New Zealand Herald , a study done by researcher Dr. Kristin Murray of Massey University claims to have "debunked stereotypes about workers of different generations" who "may have more in common than we may think." She found that though there were cultural differences between those in their twenties and those in their mid-thirties, "those cultural differences weren't reflected in underlying values and motivations." But, she found that Generation X-ers (1965–1981) and Baby Boomers (1946–1964) were "most alike." However, Dr. Murray clarifies that her study "focused on values, so there could still be differences in behavior between age groups." Jason Walker, who is the New Zealand managing director for job recruitment company Hays, disagrees with Dr. Murray's findings. His company's research showed that Generation X members worked their way up the corporate ladder, advancing by learning new job skills. The Baby Boomers were dependent on their employers to take care of them if they worked hard. The "technologically savvy" Millennials, conversely, were "more risk-taking in their careers" and expected "fast-paced results." If they weren't challenging enough, or if they felt like they were in a dead-end job, they would move on.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news | first = Heather | last = McCracken | title = Gen X &amp;amp; Y Want Same Things From Ideal Job | date = 2013-12-03 | publisher = APN New Zealand Ltd | url = http://www.nzherald.co.nz/lifestyle/news/article.cfm?c_id=6&amp;amp;objectid=11166305 | work = [[The New Zealand Herald]] | accessdate = 2013-02-16 | quote = Gen X, born between 1965 and 1981}}&lt;/ref&gt;  See also  List of generations    Demographics of the United States    Generation gap   Notes     Further reading  Generation X Goes Global: Mapping a Youth Culture in Motion, Christine Henseler, Ed.; 2012      </text>
</raw_text>